DAN ENGEL

Fullstack Web Developer

0928-675-579

im@dan-engel.fyi

dan-engel.fyi

github.com/dengel29

SUMMARY

Bilingual (English + Chinese) web developer. Does best work with others as either team player or leader. Strong sense for planning user-friendly experiences while keeping code clean and performant. Love discovering new libraries but always look for vanilla solutions first.

Track record of creative problem-solving from 2 years of building APIs and proxies for applications in China and personal projects. Also a teacher, hackathon participant, and active member of the local coding community.

TECH STACK

Web Tools + Frameworks Ruby on Rails, Express.js, WeChat 小程序, Webpack

UI + StyleCSS3, SCSS/SASS, Bootstrap,
Figma, Sketch

DB + ORMPostgresSQL, ActiveRecord,
SQLite

Project Mgmt / VersioningJira, AirTable, Trello, BitBucket,
GitHub

Professional Experience

FREELANCE

Remote Jan 2017 - Present

Backend Dev + WeChat Specialist Two most recent projects.

Livestream Integration

- Express.js and Phaser app providing livestreamers in-stream "pets" to encourage fan interaction
- ☑ Used websockets to listen for in-stream events, such as donations and subscriptions, triggering animations
- Phaser 2 code updated and refactored for Twitch and Mixer streaming services, now running in production

Reproductive Services Onboarding (ongoing)

- Connected Ruby on Rails API to WeChat Miniprogram front-end, with admin dashboard
- Assist with Tencent's MiniProgram approval process, Chinese server purchase, and deployment

LE WAGON

Chengdu - Shenzhen Dec 2017 - Present

Bootcamp Manager + Teacher

Dec 2017 - Pr

Le Wagon is a 9-week fullstack, product-driven bootcamp

Organizing and Advocating

- ✓ Write and present instructional livecodes on topics such as Making Your First Landing Page and WeChat APIs

Teaching and Mentoring

- ☑ Subjects include OOP, command line, git flow, relational databases, SQL, and the Active Record pattern
- Organized a biweekly post-bootcamp meetup for exchanging knowledge and experiences

Education

Boston University

Boston

Major: East Asian Studies + Chinese

∰ Sept 2007 - May 2011

Distinctions: Cum Laude

CET Intensive Chinese Program

Hangzhou

Distinctions: Most Improved

Sept 2010 - Dec 2010